♪〜
〜♪
（ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード）
ガハッ ゴホッ ゴホッ
Don't force it down.
You have no tolerance.
（ニコラス･Ｄ･ウルフウッド）
強ないくせに 無理すんな
It's not fair to the booze
to drink it like that.
そないな飲み方しとったら
酒がかわいそうやんか
かあっ　結構 効くなあ これ
Hey, this is some
hooch you got here!
んっ？
ふう… わいらは
できるだけのことはやった
We did everything we could.
If you have to
call it something...
それで ああなった いうんやったら
それは運命いうもんやで
...call it fate.
Don't label it with
such a simple word.
（ヴァッシュ）
そんな簡単な言葉で
片づけないでくれ
So many died.
They won't come back.
何人も死んで…
もう戻ってこない
It's more than I can bear.
僕には…
重すぎる
（銃声）
（ヴァッシュ）僕が… ブラドを
I killed Brad.
No, you didn't.
（ジェシカ）
ううん そんなことない
You didn't, but...
そんなこと ないけど…
I'm sorry!
ごめんなさい
Everyone who touches me dies.
（ヴァッシュ）
僕に関わると人が死ぬ
Maybe, but there's
somewhere you have to go.
そやけど お前には
行かなあかん所がある
You can't stop.
止まれへん わけがある
Right?
ちゃうのんか？
Yes. That's right.
ああ　そうだ
俺は やつに
会わなければならない
I have to face him.
Ah, there it is!
（ウルフウッド）
ああ 見えてきたで
We finally arrived.
やっと 着きよったな
Hear, hear! I'll have a pudding
a la mode and a mocha frosty!
（ミリィ･トンプソン）
はい はーい
プリンアラモードと
モカフロスティーでーす
I take it this means you're hungry?
すなわち
腹が減っとるっちゅうことやな
That's amazing...
How could you tell?
すごい…
どうして分かるんですかあ？
（ウルフウッド）
あんたのことやったら
何でも分かるで！ マイハニー
I know everything
about you, honey.
Forget it! Sextuplets are
out of the question, dear.
（ミリィ）ヤダよ
６つ子産むのは
大変なんですよ あなた
Nice comeback!
（ウルフウッド）
ええ リアクションやあ
（ミリィ）ウフフフッ
（ウルフウッド）アッハッハッハ
（メリル･ストライフ）
あっ… あのお
Um...
Yes?
なんだい？
あっ　いえ その…
Uh, it's nothing really...
Hello! Is anybody in there?
（ウルフウッド）
おーい 誰かおらんのか？
Hello!
おーい
Who's there?
（監視）誰だ！
Poor, unfortunate travellers
wandering the desert!
砂漠を さすろうとる
難儀な旅人や
Excuse me, but
might we come inside?
すみませんが
中に入れてもらえませんか？
I'll let you in for $ $300,000!
（監視）
30万ダブドル払ったら入れてやる
That's so much!
そんな大金(たいきん)…
ねえのが分かってるから
言ってるのさ
Exactly! I know
you haven't got it!
I'm saying,
you're not coming in!
つまり ここには入るなってことだ
んっ なんや いきなり
物騒やんか
Why all the sudden hostility?
We're not dangerous!
I'm Meryl Stryfe from the Berna...
怪しい者ではありません
私はベルナルデリ保険協会の…
（銃声）
（メリル）うわあっ
I don't care if you're
from Bernardelli or the Feds!
たとえベルナルデリだろうと
連邦政府の役人だろうと—
You're not coming in!!
ダメなもんはダメだ！
This is too one-sided!
一方的すぎるで
- Let's go.
- What?
（ヴァッシュ）行こう
（ウルフウッド）なんやて？
The people of this town probably
have their reasons for doing this.
きっと この町の人たちにも—
そうしなければならない
事情があるんだ
Isn't he over it yet?
まだ引きずっとるんか
あのアホは…
あっ
Can I help you?
なんか用かい？
（ビート）あっ はっ…
はっ　ああ… ううう
（ヴァッシュ）あっ 大丈夫か？
Are you all right?
あっ！
Aren't you going to
thank the nice man?
お兄ちゃんに ありがとうは？
（ビート）うう ああっ あっ…
Say "thank you."
ありがとうは？
あ… ありがとう
Thank you.
That was very good!
はい よくできました　あれ…
Huh?
Hey!
（ヴァッシュ）
おい そっちは砂漠だぞ！
It's only desert that way!
Let's take a little side trip.
ちょっと寄り道しようやないか
（ヴァッシュ）え？
Come on, let's go.
さあ 行きますわよ
H-Hey!
ちょっ ちょっと
（ノックする音）
Excuse us!
（ウルフウッド）邪魔するでえ
うわっ うっ なんや！
うあああ
What?!
Get out! Get the
hell out of here!!
（リッチー）
出てけ　ここから出ていけ！
Yeah, yeah!
待て 待てって…
別に怒っとるわけやない
Wait! Hey, wait!
We're not mad at you!
We got turned away
from that town, too!
わいらも あの町から
追い出されたクチや
Just let us stay here
for a little while!!
ちょっ ちょっとのあいだで
ええさかい 泊めてえな
I won't ask it as a favor!
タダとは言わん！
これで どうや
How do these strike you?
（子どもたち）ああ…
うわあ！
（ウルフウッド）
フフン 商談成立やなあ
So, we have a deal.
Mr. Wolfwood, those were
our emergency rations...
ウルフウッドさん
これは非常用の…
This is an emergency, isn't it?
今が非常事態やろ
あ…
（ヴァッシュ）アハハハッ
確かに非常事態だな
This is definitely an emergency.
はあ… まったく なんて
出たとこ勝負な人たちでしょ フッ
I swear, I've never met
such disorganized people.
（ミリィ）
わーい わーい フハハッ
Yay, yay!
Milly, what are you doing?
ミリィ　何やってるんですの？
You want some too, ma'am?
They're really, really good!
先輩もどうです？
おいしいですよ
アハハ…
I see. These kids
are all orphans, huh?
（ヴァッシュ）そうか
あの子たちは全員 孤児なのか
Yeah. It's really
a huge coincidence...
（リッチー）うん
本当に偶然なんだけど
...but we all gathered here
in the last three months.
僕たちこの３か月ぐらいのあいだに
ここに集まったんです
That sort of thing
has been known to happen.
あるんやなあ
そういうことが
You've been a great help!
でも 本当に助かりました
食べ物 少なくなってたから
We didn't have much to eat.
We're just lending
a helping hand.
困ったときは お互い様や
Why won't they
let you in the town?
しかし どうして町に
入れてもらえないんだい？
They won't let outsiders in,
even if they're only children.
よそ者は たとえ子どもでも
入れてくれません
The townsfolk are frightened.
町の人たちは おびえているんです
（ウルフウッド）なんでや？
Why?
I don't know.
（リッチー）分かりません
However, every town in this
region has been abandoned...
だけど この地方の町は—
あそこのキーバス以外
人がいないんです
...except for Keybas over there.
My town was abandoned, too.
僕の町もそうでした
One day, without any warning,
everyone began to walk out of town.
ある日 突然—
みんな町の外に向かって
歩き出したんです
（リッチー）荷物も持たずに…
口も利かないで
They didn't take a thing with them,
and didn't say a word.
（リッチー）あっ
Dad? Dad, what's wrong?!
父さん！ 父さん どうしたの？
何があったの？
答えてよ　ハッ！
What happened?!
Say something!!
What are you all doing?
何してんの みんな
父さん
Dad!
あっ えっ？
Mom...
母さん…
Mom!!!
母さーん　父さーん
Dad!!!
They all walked out of town...
何かに操られるように—
...as if something
were controlling them.
父さんたちは
町から出ていきました
All the others
went through the same thing.
ここにいる みんなも
同じ経験をしています
Tell me one thing.
（ヴァッシュ）１つ教えてくれ
Did you see anyone there
other than the townsfolk?
君は見なかったか
町の人以外の誰かを
No...
ううん
...but I did hear a voice.
ただ… 声が聞こえた
声？
A voice?
It said,
"This is what you get...
“ぐずぐずしているから
こういうことになるんだよ”って
...for taking so long."
It's him.
（ヴァッシュ）あの男か…
Boy, he never gets
a break, does he?
（ウルフウッド）次から次へと
ようやってくれるわ まったく…
What you gonna do?
Are you going in?
どないすんねん？ 行くんか？
（ビートとマイク）
よいしょ よいしょ
おお？
（ヴァッシュ）ハハッ
（２人）ああ…
Aw...
ありゃあ
No kid warms up to a guy
with an empty smile.
からっぽな笑い方しか
せえへんやつに—
子どもがなつくわけあらへん
Pass it here!
I'll carry it for you!
おら 貸してみい
わいが持ったるさかい
- C'mon, let's go.
- Huh?
（ビートとマイク）行こ 行こ
（ウルフウッド）あら？
You were saying
something about kids?
子どもがなんだって？
Oh, shut up!
They're just a little shy.
う… うるさいなあ
ちょっとシャイなだけやんか
（拍手）
（２人）ああん？
（ミリィ）えらい えらい
ちゃんとお手伝いできるんだ
Good for you!
You're great at helping out!
（ビートとマイク）
ヒャハハハッ ヘヘヘッ
So, if you cut
with the knife...
（メリル）こうやって
筋に直角に包丁を入れて—
...along the tendon at
a right angle like so...
...and sprinkle on
a lot of pepper...
少し多めにペッパーを
ふりかけておくと—
...it will last a lot
longer than you'd think.
意外に長持ちするんですのよ
Wow!
（キャロルとクリス）へえ！
Women are a marvel.
女は偉大や
Yup.
だな
Hey, hey! What'cha cookin'?
ねえねえ 何 作ってんの？
That's our secret
until supper time.
（メリル）夜まで ないしょですわ
- Yeah!
- How could you be so cold?
（キャロルとクリス）ねえ！
（ヴァッシュ）つれないぞ 君たち
That guy is a lot of trouble.
ホンマ 手間のかかるやっちゃで
（ヴァッシュたちの笑い声）
Hey, don't spill it!
（メリル）はい どうぞ
Help yourself!
（ミリィ）おいしい
This is yummy!
Let me get that.
（ビート）ほら こぼしてるぞ
（ヴァッシュ）最高！
（ウルフウッド）うまいな これも
Hey, this ain't bad either!
（マイクの寝言）
ぐっすり眠ってるなあ
They're all fast asleep.
It's probably been a long time
since they could relax.
張り詰めとったもんが
取れたんやろ
Just look at those faces.
ええ 寝顔や
（ビート）うっ うっ…
Mom... Dad...
お母さん お父さん
If I take too long,
they'll make another move.
（ヴァッシュ）
ぐずぐずしてると
また やつらが動きだす
Still...
だけど…
...we can't leave these kids.
ほっとけないよな
Hey, cheer up.
Let's have a drink.
暗い顔すんな
一杯やろうやないか
あっ？
Hey, what are you doing?!
おい！ 何をしている
うおっ
（銃声）
（監視）うわあーっ
- What was that?
- I heard a gunshot!
（住民Ａ）なんだ？ 銃声がしたぞ
（住民Ｂ）どっちだ
- Where did it come from?
- I don't know. Let's go check.
（住民Ｃ）おい 行ってみようぜ
（近づくトマの足音）
（発砲音）
（子どもたちの悲鳴）
Everyone, get away
from the windows!
みんな窓から離れて
何なんですか？ 先輩
What's going on, ma'am?!
Get away from the windows!
窓から離れるんですのよ！
Is everyone okay?!
みんな無事か？
Get down!!
（ウルフウッド）伏せんかい
ひっ ひっ　うわああ
（住民Ａ）出てこい
Come on out!!
We know you're in there!
お前らがそこにいるのは
分かってんだ
If you
don't come out by the count of 10...
10数えるあいだに出てこなければ
こっちから行くぞ
...we're coming in after you!
- Ten!
- What's the plan?
（住民Ａ）10　９…
（ウルフウッド）どないする？
Reasoning is the only way
out of a misunderstanding.
誤解を解くには
話し合う以外ないでしょ
Reason with those hotheads?
あないにヒートしてる連中にか？
Can't you come up
with anything better?
もっと ええ方法ないんか？
Never mind, I'll go alone.
いいよ 僕１人で行くから
- Three!
（住民Ａ）３　２　１
Two!
One!
ああっ
Uh, we don't know what
we did to upset you.
あの… こんなことされる覚えが
全くないんだけど—
Would you tell us
what this is about?
事情を説明してくんない？
You're pretending to be nice
to these kids as camouflage...
ガキどもに優しいふりして
カモフラージュか
...you pieces of trash!!
このクズども！
あっ！
アハッ 何のことか
分かんないんすけど…
I have no idea what
you're talking about.
（打撃音）
（ヴァッシュ）だああっ
（住民Ｂ）しらばっくれんな
Don't play dumb with us!
You're the only ones near town!
町の近くにいるのは
おめえらしかいねえんだよ
Hold on, all of you!
ちょっと待てや お前ら
うっ ああっ　うああっ
We didn't do anything!
お… 俺たちは
何もしていない
Don't play the Mr. Nice Guy!
（住民Ａ）善人面(づら)するんじゃねえ
Jeffrey was killed!
He was my best friend!!
殺されたジェフリーは
俺の親友だったんだぞ！
ぐあああ がっ…
（ウルフウッド）こ… この
勘違いだらけのヘタレどもが！
Why, you...
...bunch of blundering
ignorant idiots!!
（ヴァッシュ）よせ！
Don't!
くっ　お人よしも大概にせい
ぐああっ
Give the
goody-goody routine a rest!!!
（２人）ヒイイッ
Please... hear me out...
頼む 話を…
You pieces of shit!
けっ このクソ野郎が
（ミリィ）ハアッ
（ヴァッシュ）話を…
Hear me out...
（地響き）
（住民たち）なっ なんだ
What?!
What is that?!
どうした？ なんだよ
うわあああっ
（ヴァッシュ）あっ
（ミリィ）ハッ
What are worms doing here?!
（住民Ａ）
な… なんでワムズが こんな所に
うわっ！
うああっ
あ… あんた
Y-You...
この辺は岩盤厚いんや
なかったんかあ？
Isn't this area
solid bedrock?!
（ヴァッシュ）そのはずさ
だから家が建ってる
It has to be. They couldn't
build a house on it otherwise.
（ウルフウッド）ほんなら
なんであいつら ここにおんねん
Then what are they doing here?
I don't know. At any rate,
it isn't safe here!
分からない…
いずれにしても
ここも安全じゃない
We'll act as decoys!
Get the kids out!
僕たちがおとりになる
子どもたちを！
Understood.
分かりましたわ
You'll let us into
your town, won't you?
町に入れてもらえますわね？
Yes.
あっ… ああ
Now that's settled...
そうと決まれば
...let's get to it.
やるしかないわな
Good luck.
（ビート）頑張ってね
（ヴァッシュ）ああ
Thanks.
（ウルフウッド）わあーっ
（ヴァッシュ）こっちこっち
Over here!
（ヴァッシュ）わあああ
（ウルフウッド）ああ 助けて
Help!
Good wormies!
（ヴァッシュ）いい子だ
They're catching up, you idiot!
（ウルフウッド）
追いつかれとるがな　アホ
あ… あれも殺さへんのか？
Can't I kill those either?!
Of course not!
当然です
Do I have to do it your way?!
つきあわなあかんのか
（ヴァッシュとウルフウッド）
ぎゃあ　うわあああ
Hey, what are these?! Don't you
find they're awfully well organized?
おい なんや　こいつら
変にまとまっとらへんか？
Definitely.
確かに！
He's out there somewhere...
（ウルフウッド）
どっかにおるんやで—
Some rotten blighter is watching
as they do his dirty work!
あいつら使(つこ)て
高みの見物しとる ど腐れが
まさか！
Do you suppose?!
How did worms get
inside the town?!
（メリル）
どうして町にまでワムズが…
（子どもたち）うわあっ
（発砲音）
（爆発音）
Onto the rooftops!
（ヴァッシュ）建物に上れ！
（ミリィとメリル）えっ？
高い場所なら攻撃も届かないはずだ
If you get high enough,
they won't be able to reach you!
R-Right!
（メリル）は… はい！
（子どもたちの逃げ惑う声）
What's wrong?
Are you hurt?
どうしたの？ ケガしたの？
（マイク）うううっ…
Oh, dear...
（ミリィ）あらら…
Hey, come back!
あっ 待って
（ヴァッシュ）あっ…
（ウルフウッド）任せえ！
I'm on it!
This is horrible...
なんてこった
Our town...
俺たちの町が…
あっ… ミリィたちは？
Where are Milly and the boy?
It's all right.
He's with them.
大丈夫さ あいつがついてる
That's true...
そうですわね
But what is this?
（ヴァッシュ）しかし なんだ
I keep having the sensation
that something doesn't belong.
さっきから体に感じる
この奇妙な違和感は…
（衝撃音）
（発砲音）
Damn! There's too many of them!
クソ　数が多すぎる
（銃声）
あっ！
（住民Ａ）うわあああ
（ヴァッシュ）あっ！
Wait!
（ミリィ）待って！
I caught you!
（ミリィ）はい 捕まえた
（マイク）うわーん
It's all right.
It's nothing to be ashamed of.
（ミリィ）大丈夫
恥ずかしくなんかないんだからね
（ウルフウッド）フッ
（住民Ａ）うわああ
（メリル）うわっ
Out of bullets!
弾(たま)切れ
So that's it!
そうか
（銃声）
（ミリィ）はうっ
（マイク）うううっ
（ミリィ）はあっ
（２人）ああ…
What the...
なんや？
You were controlling them
with a high-frequency device.
高周波で操っていたのか
Why? Why are
you doing this?
なぜだ？
なぜ君がこんなことをする？
（ビート）
フフッ… それは僕が—
Because I...
...am a Gung-Ho Gun!
ガンホーガンズだからさ！
あっ！
I am the fourth Gun-Ho Gun,
Zazie the Beast.
ガンホーガンズの４(フォー)
ザジ･ザ･ビースト
You're kidding...
えっ ウソ…
（キャロルの泣き声）
（ザジ）泣くな！
Don't cry!
フンッ うっとうしい
僕は子どもが嫌いだ
God, that's annoying!
I hate children.
They get weepy, depressed,
and brush their teeth when told...
すぐ泣く 落ち込む
歯を磨けと言われれば
そのとおりにしか行動しない
...because they're too
stupid to do otherwise!
They lack free will!
自由意志が欠落している！
（銃声）
You probably
can't comprehend...
（ザジ）君には どうして
こんな手の込んだマネをしたか—
...why I did something
so intricate.
理解できないだろうねえ
やめろ！
Don't!!
（ザジ）フッ
Bete!
（リッチー）ビート！
The name's Zazie!
Zazie the Beast!
ザジだよ
ザジ･ザ･ビーストだ
You're forcing yourself.
君は無理をしているよ
ああ？
You cried last night.
昨日の晩 泣いてたよね？
（銃声）
（ヴァッシュ）ぐっ ううっ
You tried to cheer me on
a little while ago.
さっき 僕を
励ましてくれたじゃないか
As a demon, I am able to block off
my consciousness and memory.
魔人なら意識や記憶を
封鎖することもできるんだよ
I don't believe that.
（ヴァッシュ）信じないよ
You're forcing yourself
to do this, aren't you?
君は無理をしているんだ
そうだろ？
What an idiot of
a goody-two-shoes!
どうしようもない
お人よしのバカだ
Okay, die thinking
your pleasant little thoughts.
なら その独りよがりな考えを
抱きながら死になよ
Stop it, Bete!
やめて ビート
うっ ううう…
ぐうっ
（銃声）
あっ！
ああっ！
あっ…
How could you?!
あなたは！
なぜだ…
Why?
Why did you shoot him?!
なぜ撃った
Kids are kids,
but he was a demon.
ガキはガキでも—
あいつも魔人や
いうやんか
If I didn't shoot him,
that would be you lying there.
わいが
撃たへんかったら—
ああなったんは
お前のほうやで
You're wrong.
He wasn't going to shoot me.
違う…
あの子に
撃つ気はなかった
Stop glossing it over
with your childish logic!!
ガキみたいな理屈で—
自分勝手なキレイ事
ほざくな！
You are wrong.
君は…
間違ってる
（殴る音）
（ヴァッシュ）ぐはっ あっ
What alternative do I have?
ほかに方法がないやろが…
We're searching for a place.
（ヴァッシュ）僕らは求めている
穏やかな日常が続き—
A place where we can
live peaceful days...
A place with no wars,
nor stealing...
争いもなく 奪うこともなく
A place where people
can live as people.
人が人として
生きられる場所を
こないな…
Don't...
Don't tell me your dreams
in a place like this!!
こないな場所で
理想なんか語るな！
ああ…
♪〜
〜♪
（ヴァッシュ）
間違いに気づくこと
ウソをつかないこと
To realize a mistake.
To not lie.
To love one another.
To not kill.
相手を慈しむこと
人を殺さないこと
Those are very simple things,
but the times won't allow for them.
とても簡単なことだ
でも時代がそれを許さない
この星には緑がない
There is no green on this planet,
even though we want it...
僕たちは
あの場所を求めているのに
...though we want it so badly.
こんなにも求めているのに
A place where we can live peaceful days,
with no wars nor stealing...
そこでは穏やかな日常が続き
争いもなく 奪うこともなく
...a sacred place where people
can live as people.
人が人として生きられる聖地
Yes, there.
That place is called...
そう そこは…
その場所の名は…